I am the chef here.
（四宮小次郎(しのみやこじろう)）シェフは俺だ
Underlings like you have no right to make changes to my recette!
俺が作ったルセットに
手を加えることが―
下っ端に許されるわけねえだろ！
Tadokoro Megumi.
田所恵
You're fired.
クビだ
（幸平創真(ゆきひらそうま)）くっ
Cooking Battle.
食戟(しょくげき)…
Cooking Battle
If I beat you in a Cooking Battle,
食戟で あんたを負かしたら―
will you rescind Tadokoro's expulsion?
田所の退学―
（創真）取り消してくんないすか？
（田所恵(たどころめぐみ)）ああっ…
A Cooking Battle?
食戟…
ハッ 懐かしい響きだ
Now that brings back memories!
What the hell is the transfer student thinking?
（男子生徒Ａ）何考えてんだ
編入生のやつ
He'll be up against an alumnus,
（男子生徒Ｂ）相手は卒業生
元十傑(じゅっけつ) 第一席
a former first seat of the Elite Ten at that!
Plus, Chef Shinomiya is a seasoned veteran from the front lines of the culinary world!
（男子生徒Ｃ）しかも―
Shinomiya Kojirou
Chef at French restaurant SHINO'S
食の最前線で戦ってる怪物
四宮シェフだぞ
A Cooking Battle with an opponent who's not currently a student is not without precedent.
在校生以外との食戟
前例がないわけじゃない
But it does require the consent
of both parties, doesn't it?
…が “食戟には
双方の合意が必要”だろ？
I'm afraid that I have no intention
of accepting your challenge.
悪いが
勝負を受ける気はないんでねぇ
There is nothing you can do.
お前が どうあがこうと
田所恵の退学は決定事項…
Tadokoro Megumi's expulsion is final—
Well, let's not be too hasty.
（堂島銀(どうじまぎん)）まあ そう 急(せ)くな
（四宮）ん？
Looks like you have quite an interesting situation developing here, Shinomiya.
なかなか面白いことに
なっているようだな 四宮
（乾日向子(いぬいひなこ)）んっ？
Doujima-san?
堂島さん
The Magician from the East
Office
Hm, I see.
（堂島）うん なるほど
Office
（乾）あむっ
う～ん おいしいじゃないですか
田所恵さんの品
Inui Hinako
Japanese restaurant, Kirinoya
Tadokoro Megumi-san's dish is delicious!
Why not just let her pass?
これなら合格にしてあげても
いいでしょう？
You're so stubborn, Shinomiya-senpai!
四宮先輩の頑固者～
How mule-headed!
頭でっかち～
Narcissist!
ナルシスト
Poser!
ええカッコしい
黙ってろ 日向子
Shut up, Hinako.
S-Sorry.
（乾）ごごごごご…
ごめんなさい
はあ… ありゃ…
It hurts.
Doujima-san, I believe I was given full discretion for this task.
堂島さん この課題は
俺に一任されてるはずだぜ
Of course, Shinomiya.
（堂島）もちろんだ 四宮
I have no complaints about the nature of the task or your evaluation criteria.
お前が定めた試験内容と
判定基準に不満はないさ
However, she did try to deal
with the situation at hand.
だが少なくとも彼女は
状況に対処しようとしたんだろ？
Don't you think her courage might merit a certain degree of consideration?
そのガッツには
一考の余地があるとは思わないか？
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
I don't.
（四宮）思わないね
（恵）あっ…
Not in the least.
ちっとも思わない
I do! Give her another chance!
私は余地あると思いま～す！
Wow, it seems that we have a tie.
む！　なんとこれで同票だ
のっぴきならんな
We are at an impasse.
You guys...
（四宮）こいつら…
I'm left with no choice.
（堂島）致し方ない
I'll oversee the unofficial Cooking Battle.
アンオフィシャルの食戟
俺が取り仕切ろう
Think of it as a street brawl.
いわば野試合だな
However, we cannot let it interfere with the training camp.
（堂島）しかし合宿の―
プログラムを乱すわけには
いかんから―
Once all the afternoon tasks are complete,
今日午後の課題を
すべて消化した後―
the two of you will face Shinomiya.
君ら２人と四宮で
戦ってもらおう
Hold on a minute, Doujima-san!
おい 待ってくれよ 堂島さん
Why do I have to participate in this farce—
何で俺がそんな茶番を…
Just play along, Shinomiya.
受けろ 四宮
Fine, fine.
分かったよ　ムッシュ堂島の
気まぐれに付き合うさ
I'll accede to Monsieur Doujima's whims.
Okay, Yukihira.
オーケー 幸平
If you win, I'll rescind her expulsion.
お前が勝てば
彼女の退学は取り下げよう
But if you lose, you'll be expelled
right along with her.
ただし―
負ければお前のクビも
まとめて飛ばす
So there you have it.
（堂島）…というわけだ
Come to the annex's basement
when you're done.
後で別館の地下を訪ねてくれ
Let's see your mettle.
君らの価値を見せてもらう
Well, looks like we're still here
by the skin of our teeth.
いやぁ～ 何とか首の皮１枚
つながったなぁ
For now, let's do our best and get through the afternoon session, Tadokoro.
とりあえずは午後の課題も
しっかり頑張ろうぜ 田所
Glare...
Souma-kun, how could you be so stupid?!
（恵）創真君のバカ！
（創真）おおおっ うっ！
How could you make an insane challenge like that?!
（恵）なして あんな
むちゃな勝負挑んだのさ？
はあ… 創真君は
合格してたんだから
You passed!
うっ うっ… あたしなんか
So you...
You shoulda just lemme be!
ほっとけばよかったべさ
Tadokoro.
（創真）田所
So your dialect slips out sometimes, huh?
お前 たまに方言
出る時あるよな～
Why are you bringing that up now?!
（創真）ハハハハハ
（恵）それ今 言うこと？
Come on, on your feet.
（創真）ほら 立ちなよ
We'd better not be late to the afternoon session.
課題の開始時間に遅れちまうぜ
（恵）いつも助けて
もらっているのに―
You're always helping me out,
and now I've dragged you into this mess.
こんなことに巻き込んじゃって
I don't know how I'll ever make it up to you.
私 何て謝ったらいいか…
You don't need to.
別に
It was my own decision,
so you don't need to apologize.
俺が勝手にやったことだし
謝ることねえけど
Besides, the reason
I challenged him should be obvious.
それに
なんで勝負を挑んだかって―
決まってんじゃん
It's because you're not meant to drop out here.
（創真）田所は こんなところで
落ちていいやつじゃないからだ
Well?
（榊涼子(さかきりょうこ)）どうだった？
Nope, she wasn't in our room either.
（吉野悠姫(よしのゆうき)）ダメだ～
部屋にもいなかったよ
I can't reach her cell.
電話も つながらないわ
That's really weird.
おっかしいな～
恵 何かあったのかなぁ？
I wonder if something happened to Megumi.
Everyone should be done
with the afternoon session.
（丸井善二(まるいぜんじ)）午後の課題は
どの組も終了したはずだが
Maybe she...
まさか…
I didn't see her name
on the list of people who failed.
（伊武崎峻(いぶさきしゅん)）不合格者リストに
名前は なかった
Why don't we ask people who were in the same sessions as her?
（佐藤昭二(さとうしょうじ)）
同じ課題を受けたやつに
聞いてみっかぁ？
Oh, right!
（悠姫）そうだ
幸平が一緒なんじゃないの？
Wasn't Yukihira with her?
So where's Yukihira?
幸平は？
Come to think of it, I haven't seen him.
（青木大吾(あおきだいご)）そういや 見てねえな
Hm....
Those two managed to get themselves
into a Cooking Battle over Don RS.
あの２人 この間も
丼研絡みで食戟やらかしたよね
Well, that was mostly Yukihira-kun's fault.
（涼子）…というか 幸平君がね
I have a really bad feeling about this!
（終了のベル）
（６人）嫌な予感しかしない
There are no plans to use this hotel's annex for the training camp.
（堂島）ホテル遠月(とおつき)離宮の別館は
今回の―
合宿で使用される予定はない
（２人の足音）
その地下１階 厨房(ちゅうぼう)
You're in the basement kitchen.
No one will interfere.
ここなら邪魔は入らない
Just a Spectator
Wh-Why are all the alumni here?
ど… どうして卒業生の皆さんが？
I asked them to serve as judges.
審査員として来てもらった
Just a Spectator
I suspect Inui might be biased.
（堂島）乾では どうも
判定が偏りそうだからな
Just a Spectator
Donato Gotouda
Auberge, Tesoro
An unofficial Cooking Battle
in the middle of a training camp?
（ドナート悟桐田(ごとうだ)）合宿の最中に
非公式の食戟とはね
Not to mention, one between
an alumnus and a current student.
しかも卒業生ＶＳ(ヴァーサス)在校生
What would Chappelle-sensei do if he found out?
シャペル先生に知れたら
どうなりますかな？
I bet he'd bite our heads off.
Sekimori Hitoshi
Sushi restaurant, Ginza Hinowa
（関守平(せきもりひとし)）怒られるだろうな
こっぴどく
Mizuhara Fuyumi
Italian restaurant, Ristorante F
If he finds out about this, I'm going to run.
（水原冬美(みずはらふゆみ)）もしもバレたら
私は逃げる
I'll say it's all Shinomiya's fault.
全部 四宮のせいにする
I heard that, Mizuhara!
聞こえてんぞ 水原 コラァ！
We will now have an unofficial
match, two against one.
では ただ今より
２対１の野試合を執り行う
Use the vegetables and other ingredients
left over from today's sessions to make the dish.
今日の課題で余った野菜類
これを使った料理をお題とする
You may make anything you like,
作るメニューは自由だが―
but try to use vegetables as the main ingredient.
なるべく野菜が
メインになる品にしてくれ
The time limit is two hours.
制限時間は２時間とする
I am the reason for this Cooking Battle.
（恵）この食戟の
原因を作ったのは私
I can't let Souma-kun get expelled over this.
それで創真君が退学になるなんて
絶対にイヤだ
I'll do my best not to drag him down—
せめて足を引っ張らないように…
There's one more condition.
（堂島）更にもう１つ条件をつける
Tadokoro Megumi.
田所恵
You will be the master chef.
君がメインで調理するんだ
What?
You will decide the recipe on your own.
（堂島）レシピは君１人で決めろ
Yukihira, you'll be the sous-chef supporting her.
幸平はサブとしてサポートに回れ
What?!
Very well!
それでは食戟―
Let the Cooking Battle...
（堂島）開戦だ！
（恵）あ～っ！
begin!
Doujima-senpai!
（創真）堂島先輩
I'm the one who issued the challenge!
食戟 挑んだのは俺っすよ
So why that condition?
なのに なんで？
You had no basis for issuing your challenge, yet I made it happen anyway.
もともと成立しない勝負を
俺が取り持ったんだ
There's no room to negotiate.
俺の出す条件ものんでもらう
だけど…
But—
Yukihira! Suppose you win
this match with your cooking,
幸平
君の料理で勝ち
田所が生き延びたとしよう
and Tadokoro's expulsion is rescinded.
（創真）くっ…
（堂島）それが何になる？
But then what?
She'll still be your sidekick.
金魚のフンであることは変わらん
Soon enough she'll find herself
kicked out of another session.
（堂島）早晩 別の課題で
蹴落とされるだけだろう
Will you save her next time, Yukihira? And the time after that?
これからも
幸平に助けてもらうのか？
At Tohtsuki, everyone must demonstrate their worth through their own skills.
遠月学園では己の価値は
その腕で証明しなければならない
Whether you deserve to stay is up to you to prove.
ここに残る人材か否か―
それを示すべきは君自身
So tonight,
今夜 この時
この調理台において―
at this time,
and at this workstation,
Tadokoro-kun,
田所君 君が料理長(シェフ)だ
you're the chef.
Doujima-san.
（四宮）堂島さん
（恵）あっ
I already know what I'm going to make.
（四宮）
俺はもう作る品を決めました
May I begin?
（四宮）先に調理を始めても？
（堂島）ああ 構わない
Go ahead.
Heh! I feel for you, Yukihira.
（四宮）フッ 同情するぜ 幸平
What do you mean?
（創真）何がすか？
It's only natural to be in despair.
絶望的な気分だろ？
Your fate is riding on that half-wit's skills.
そのノロマの腕に自分の―
クビが かかってるんだからな
Did you hear that?!
聞きました？
今の憎たらしい言い方
He is so rude!
Shinomiya has a really nasty personality.
四宮ってホント性格悪いと思う
That's why your relationships
never last, Shinomiya-san.
そんなだから女性と
長続きしないんですよ 四宮さんは
Quiet in the peanut gallery!
（四宮）外野は黙ってろ！
（乾）ああっ！
Wait, when did you slip out of those ropes?!
（四宮）っつうか 日向子
てめえ いつの間に縄を？
Good luck, my Megumi-chan!
頑張って 私の恵ちゃん！
Don't lose to that spiteful man!
あんな陰湿男に負けるな！
Shut up!
（四宮）うるせえ！
Chef Shinomiya Kojirou.
（恵）四宮小次郎シェフ
After graduating from Tohtsuki,
遠月卒業後
単身フランスへ渡って―
he went to France and opened a restaurant in Paris,
the crucible for gourmet restaurants.
美食の激戦区パリで
店を開いている料理人
I'm facing someone like that with my recipe?!
（恵）そんな人と
私のレシピで戦う？
I... I have to calm down.
（恵）お… 落ち着かなきゃ…
I need to calm down!
落ち着かなきゃダメなのに―
I'm blanking out.
頭の中が真っ白
I can't stop shaking.
震えが止まらない
Tadokoro!
（創真）田所！
（堂島）言っておくが―
I doubt that you need the reminder,
but you're not allowed to alter her recipe.
彼女のレシピに
手を加えるのはなしだ
You are a sous-chef, nothing more.
（堂島）
お前はあくまでスー･シェフ
The assistant, understand?
副料理長だからな
You felt Tadokoro was good enough
to merit survival, didn't you?
お前は田所に生き残る価値が
あると思ったんだろ？
If you can't trust her cooking,
その彼女の料理が
信じられないというなら―
remove yourself from this match now.
今すぐ勝負から降りろ
No way.
（創真）降りるわけないでしょ
俺は料理人っすよ
I'm a chef.
No chef would ever run away from a kitchen!
料理人が厨房から
逃げ出してたまるかよ
（恵）ダメ…
A failure.
I'm a failure, after all.
やっぱり私はダメなんだ
I only made it this far because of Souma-kun.
ここまで生き残れたのも
創真君のおかげ
Hey, Tadokoro.
（創真）おい 田所
（恵）私なんか…
I'm just...
Put your hands together.
I'm just a...
（創真）合掌してみろ
（恵）私なんか…
Do it.
（創真）合掌！
（乾）あっ？
（悟桐田）オ～ウ！
痛い
Ow...
It's a trick I learned long ago.
（創真）昔 実家で習った―
When you're nervous,
doing that can help you relax.
緊張をほぐす裏技だ
The only problem is that
you can't do it by yourself.
１人じゃできねえのが
難点だけどな
That hurt, but...
（恵）痛い… けど―
I've stopped shaking.
震えが止まった
The first thing you need to do is calm down.
ま とりあえずは落ち着いてさ
Then, take as much time as you need
to figure out what to cook.
そんで何作るか
じっくり考えろよ
B-But...
（恵）で… でも―
Chef Shinomiya's dish will be French cuisine that was tempered in France.
四宮シェフが作るのは本場で
磨かれたフランス料理なんだよ
If I can't make a dish that can surpass his,
それに勝てる料理を作らなきゃ
創真君が退学に…
you'll be expelled.
My dad used to say,
（創真）俺の親父が言ってたぜ
（恵）あっ？
"Cooking is about putting all you've got out there on one plate."
（創真）“料理ってのは皿の上に
自分の全部を載っけることだ”って
Forget about what the other
guy'll be making for now.
（創真）相手が何を作るかとか―
そういうことは いったん忘れろ
But my cooking isn't...
（恵）でも私なんかの料理じゃ…
The rice balls you made for us back at
the dorm's garden were really great.
（創真）
寮の畑で食ったお前のおにぎり
本当にうまかった
（恵）あっ…
（創真）余計なことは考えんな
Don't think about stuff that doesn't matter.
Just make your own food, Tadokoro.
田所らしい料理を作りゃいいんだ
That's enough.
それでいいんだ
My own food...
私らしい料理…
Well, this is a surprise.
（四宮）おっと！ こいつは驚いた
You two still haven't started cooking?
まだ調理にすら入ってなかったのか
Your chef seems to be a real half-wit.
そちらのシェフは随分と
ノロマなようで
Why don't you wait till after you taste
her cooking before you bitch at her?
田所の悪口を言うのは
料理を食ってからにしてくれます？
Souma-kun.
（恵）創真君
（創真）おっ
Um, I think I...
あのね…
決まった
may have decided on a dish.
…かもしれない
What're you doing, Shinomiya-senpai?!
How violent!
（悠姫）卒業生と食戟？
Untie me—
ああ
田所と同じ組のやつが言ってた
If you don't shut up right
this second, I'll put a gag on you.
Silence...
Guess that got your attention.
A Cooking Battle with an alumnus?!
Yeah, a guy who was in the same session as Tadokoro told me.
But why?
（悠姫）何で？
何がどうしたらそうなんの？
How'd that even happen?
Sounds like Tadokoro was about to get expelled.
どうも田所が
クビ切られそうになって―
So then Yukihira—
それに幸平が…
Megumi's expelled?!
恵がクビ？
Ugh, no!
もう イヤ～！
（悠姫）処理できな～い！
This can't be!
Yuuki, calm down!
（涼子）悠姫 落ち着いて
（悠姫）あ～っ！
That's what I'm thinking of making.
（恵）…っていう品を
作ろうと思うんだけど
How interesting!
（創真）面白い
Really?
ほんと？ ほんとに？
Seriously?
Yay!
やったあ！
Oh, b-but this recipe would require a lot
of prep work with different ingredients,
あっ で… でもね―
このレシピだと下処理に
手間がかかる食材が多くて―
so I'm not sure we can manage.
うまく仕上げられるかどうか
Who do you think I am?
俺を誰だと思ってんだ？
I was holding the fort as the number two chef at Yukihira Diner!
“食事処ゆきひら”の
二番手 張ってた男だぜ
Well, it was only the two of us,
just my dad and me.
ま 親父と俺の
２人だけだったけどな
I'll give you everything I've got,
experience and all, to support you.
俺の経験―
全部つぎ込んでお前を支える
Just for today, we'll open Tadokoro Diner!
本日限り“食事処たどころ”
開店だ！
O-Okay!
Great!
（創真）よっしゃ～！
Let's do this,
やりますか
Chef Tadokoro!
田所シェフ！
Okay!
はい！
Tadokoro
Diner
I'll prep the tomatoes.
（恵）私はトマトを調理します
Souma-kun, please get the other ingredients ready.
創真君は
他の食材の下ごしらえを
Got it!
（創真）合点！
Shinomiya-senpai!
（乾）四宮先輩
（四宮）何だよ 日向子？
What, Hinako?
The "dokoro" in "restaurant" and
the "dokoro" in "Tadokoro" overlap.
“食事処”の“処(どころ)”と―
“たどころ”の“どころ”が
一緒で―
It makes the name really catchy!
とっても語呂がいいですね
Take her somewhere far away!
Seriously?!
（堂島）遠くに置いてこい
（乾）ねえ～ なんで～？
Why?!
I'll only get more nervous
if I focus on beating Chef Shinomiya.
（恵）
四宮シェフに勝とうなんて
気負っても緊張が増すだけ
Just focus on my own cooking.
自分の料理に集中するんだ
I'm the chef right now.
今は私が料理長(シェフ)なんだから
Oh, no!
（恵）しまった！
I was supposed to prepare the shoulder cut first!
肩肉の切り出しを
真っ先にやらなきゃ―
Now the order's all wrong—
調理の手順が…
The shoulder's done.
（創真）切り出しあがり！
I removed all the tendons too.
筋も全部 取っといた
Which do you want me to do next,
the chicken liver or the fatback?
（創真）次 鶏レバーと背脂の処理
どっちからやる？
U-Um, the liver, please!
あっ えっと…
レバーのほうからお願い
Got it!
（創真）あいよ！
（悟桐田）ううむ
Souma-kun!
創真君
蒸し焼きにする型の準備は？
Is the mold ready?
Yup!
できてる
あとはパテを仕込むだけだ
Just gotta get the pâté ready.
By the way, I'll be done sauteeing
the vegetables in twelve seconds.
ちなみに野菜のソテーは
あと12秒でできる
Th-Thanks.
あっ… ありがとう
He's amazing!
（恵）すごい
私が欲しいタイミングで―
He's delivering all the prepped ingredients to me right when I need them!
下処理の済んだ食材が
次々と手元に来る
Is this how finely you wanted it chopped?
こんくらいの粗さでいいか？
Yeah!
He's the only one helping me,
（恵）サポートが
１人ついただけなのに―
but I feel like I'm able to cook several times
faster than I'd be able to by myself.
私１人で調理するより―
何倍も速く動けているような…
What's going on?
何あれ？
He's staying several steps ahead of her and
providing support without neglecting his own tasks.
彼女の仕事を先読みして―
自分の作業との両立を崩さずに
サポートしてるな
Yet he doesn't rush ahead and
go beyond what's necessary.
しかも決して余計なことはしない
He's monitoring her very carefully
to avoid getting in her way.
田所の邪魔にならないよう―
神経を張り巡らせている
Hm, Yukihira Souma.
（関守）何… 幸平創真
He's the sole transfer student this year.
今年 ただ１人の編入生か
His family runs a diner.
実家は定食屋
It seems he was trained there.
そこで修業した経験があるようです
I find it hard to believe he gained
that much skill from helping out at home.
いや しかし家業の手伝いだけで
あの動きはあり得ない
His skill clearly surpasses that of any student.
（関守）どう見たって―
あれは学生のレベルを
はるかに超えている
Both contestants should begin finishing up!
さあ 双方 仕上げにかかれ！
We'll start plating the dish!
盛り付けに入ります
Got it!
おうよ！
（堂島）では―
We will now begin the judging.
審査を開始する
Shinomiya's dish will be presented first.
まずは四宮の料理だ
サーブを
Serve your dish.
A dish made by a Tohtsuki alumnus...
（恵）
遠月学園卒業生の料理―
I wonder how amazing it'll be.
一体どんなすごい品が
出てくるんだろう？
Well, I can't help but feel anticipation!
いやあ 期待しちゃいますねえ
Indeed.
うむ
Hm?
Chou farci!
（悟桐田）シュー･ファルシ
This is rather unexpected.
これは少し意外なメニューですね
It's from the regional cuisine of Auvergne.
オーベルニュ地方の郷土料理だな
A filling of finely chopped meat and vegetables
is wrapped in cabbage leaves, then steamed.
（関守）肉や野菜を
細かく刻んだ詰め物を―
キャベツの葉で包み蒸した―
It resembles the more familiar
cabbage roll found in Western cuisine.
洋食でいうところの
ロールキャベツに近い品
It's a dish often made in French homes.
フランスの家庭でも
よく作られる定番料理だけど…
I'm taken aback.
何か拍子抜けって感じですねぇ
I thought Shinomiya-senpai only
knew how to make fancy dishes—
いつも気取った料理ばかり作る
四宮先輩に…
Wait, where's my share?
っていうか 私の分は？
I didn't make any for you.
（四宮）ねえよ
水原の分けてもらえ
Ask Mizuhara to share.
Well, then.
（悟桐田）では…
Ah!
お～っ！
香味野菜の香りが食欲をそそる
The aroma of herbs whets the appetite.
（水原）あむっ
M... Me...
Delicious!
Meraviglioso!
メラヴィリョーゾ！
Th-This stuffing is different from the typical
pork and onion stuffing used in chou farci!
こ… この詰め物―
一般的なシュー･ファルシで
使われる豚ロースや玉ねぎではない
It's a farce of Jidori chicken breast meat!
地鶏胸肉のファルスだ
First, he butterflied the chicken breasts.
Farce
（悟桐田）
切り開いた胸肉の中に―
Then he prepared a stuffing of morels, asparagus,
and fois gras sauteed in beef fat,
牛脂で香ばしく炒めたモリーユ茸と
アスパラガス そしてフォアグラ
along with a smooth mousse-like paste made from
the chicken breast, butter, eggs, and heavy cream.
更に胸肉とバター
卵 生クリームを―
滑らかなムース状に
したものを入れ―
蒸し上げられている
The chou farci was then steamed.
This mousse coats the tongue,
（水原）このムースが
舌にねっとりと絡みつき―
then dissolves instantly into a rich burst of flavor in your mouth.
その瞬間ふわりと溶けて―
濃厚な旨味となって
口の中に広がる
And the most fearsome ingredient of all
is the cabbage that envelops the filling.
そして何より恐るべきは
周りを包むこのキャベツだ
The Savoy cabbage.
（堂島）サボイ･キャベツ
In Japan, it's called the crepe cabbage.
日本では“ちりめんキャベツ”と
呼ばれるこの食材は―
It has a strong grassy smell when raw,
生では青臭さが強いが―
but it develops a delicate,
sweet flavor once cooked.
加熱すると上質な甘みが出る品種だ
Blanchir... blanching.
“ブランシール”
“下ゆで”
Vapeur... steaming.
“ヴァプール”
“蒸し上げ”
At each step,
それぞれの工程で―
he cooked the dish at its optimal temperature.
この料理に最適なポイントへ
ピタリと合わせ加熱されている
That resulted in a delicate sweetness
that elevates the flavor of the entire dish.
そうして生み出された繊細な甘みが
味全体の品位を高めている
It's as if he cast a spell over the whole dish.
まるで魔法にかけられたように…
Immediately following graduation,
he went to France by himself.
四宮は遠月卒業と同時に
単身フランスへ渡り―
He opened a restaurant in Paris
after several years of training
数年の修行の後
パリで店を出し―
and became an owner-chef.
オーナーシェフとなった
While most dishes in French cuisine use meat,
肉料理を偏重しがちな
フランス料理にあって―
Shinomiya shone a fresh spotlight
on légumes, or vegetables,
“レギュム”
すなわち野菜に新しい光を当てた
四宮の料理は―
shocking gourmands throughout the nation.
国中の食通に衝撃を与えた
Eventually, the chef from Japan gained the respect of the residents of the capital of gourmet cooking.
やがて美食の街の住人たちは―
日本からやってきた
その料理人に敬意を込め―
He was honored with the name,
こう称えるようになった
Magician of Legumes
"The Magician of Légumes."
〝野菜料理(レギュム)の
魔術師〞と
Magician of Legumes
（乾）うう～ 悔しい
I hate to admit it...
I hate to admit it, but it's delicious!
悔しいけど美味です
He took a common regional dish and
reinterpreted it with his sharpened senses...
（悟桐田）ごく一般的な郷土料理を
研ぎ澄まされた感性で紡ぎ直し…
...and elevated it to something that could be served at a high-end restaurant.
（関守）高級レストランで出せる
レベルまで押し上げている
The light chicken mousse that melts in your mouth,
（堂島）
ふわりと溶ける鶏肉のムースと―
and the fresh sweetness of the cabbage
envelops your mouth and beyond!
それを包む
キャベツの若々しい甘さが―
口の中を…
そして体中を包んでいく
It's as if the power of this dish's flavor is coursing through your body!
舌に 体に
味の魔力がみなぎるようだ
This...
（乾）これは…
...is magic!
（関守）魔法
Indeed.
（水原）そう
Yes!
（悟桐田）まさに…
It is a spell cast by a magician from the East!
（堂島）東洋から来た
魔術師によって巻き起こる…
Légume Magic!
（審査員たち）
レギュム･マジック！
Cabbage Red.
キャベツ･レッド！
Ca...
キャ… キャベツ･ブルー
Cabbage Blue.
Cabbage Pink!
キャベツ･ピンク！
Yes!
イエス！
Magical Cabbage
M0,0,,Magical Cabbage
Magical Cabbage!
Magical Cabbage
（３人）マジカル･キャベツ！
Magic, magic!
Magical Cabbage
（関守）まほ まほ
ああ～ 堪能しました
That was fantastic.
Well done, Shinomiya-san.
さすがは四宮さん
It is no wonder that you are called
the Magician of Légumes.
（関守）まさに
レギュムの魔術師たるゆえんだな
So, how did it taste, Mizuhara?
おい どうだよ 水原
お味のほうは？
げふっ
It was perfect once I wiped
all my memories of you.
四宮に関する記憶を消して
食べられたら完璧だった
Well, how unfortunate for you.
へえ～ そいつは気の毒だ
Still, I wasn't expecting this, Shinomiya.
しかし意外だったな 四宮
I thought I'd be able to try the specialty
of your restaurant, Shino.
俺は てっきり
お前の店“SHINO'S(シノズ)”の―
スペシャリテが食えると
思っていたが
ハーッハハハハ
冗談きついですねぇ 堂島さん
That's a joke in poor taste, Doujima-san.
My opponent's only a student.
相手は まだ学生ですよ
Would I be so cruel as to serve my signature dish?
看板料理を出すなんて
そんな無慈悲なまねするとでも？
You would.
やりそうだ
You would crush them,
so that they'd never be able to cook again.
二度と料理ができなくなるほど
たたき潰しそうで～す
An up-and-coming chef who's opened a restaurant in a prime location in Paris,
（堂島）
美食の激戦区 パリの一等地に―
店を構え 戦い続ける
新進気鋭のシェフ
the battleground of gourmet food.
He believes he can't possibly lose to a student,
“この俺が学生なんかに―”
“負けることなどあり得ない”と
いう―
an arrogance that may well be justified.
至極まっとうな驕(おご)り
If he has an Achilles's heel, it'd be...
つけ入る隙があるとするなら…
All right. Tadokoro, Yukihira, serve your dish.
（堂島）では田所 幸平
君らのサーブを
'Kay.
うっす
O-Okay.
あっ はい
Our dish will finally be judged.
（恵）いよいよ―
私たちの料理の審査
Let's go, Tadokoro!
行くか 田所
Tadokoro?
（創真）田所？
I poured everything I had into this dish.
（恵）自分の精いっぱいの力を
出し切った料理―
I didn't think that having
someone judge it would be so...
それを誰かに評価されることが
こんなに―
so terrifying.
こんなに怖いなんて
I wonder what they'll say.
何て言われるんだろう？
もし まずいなんて言われたら…
What if they say it's disgusting?
I even had Souma-kun's help!
創真君も手伝ってくれたのに
ああ… ああ…
（恵）あっ？
（創真）大丈夫だ
It'll be fine.
Go!
（創真）行け
Hm?
Hm!
（悟桐田）オ～ウ？
（関守）これは…
This is...
It's a terrine!
（乾）テリーヌ！
End
Next Episode
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
（四宮）次回 ｢食戟のソーマ｣
the twelfth dish.
12品目か… ハッ…
Menu
The Memory of a Dish
The Memory of a Dish.
「ひと皿の記憶」
You're fired.
クビだ
Magical Cabbage
Yes!
Magical Cabbage!
Yeah!